Inventory of the James Robert Huntley papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Steuben-Schurz-Gesellschaft, undated (Box-folder 207: 19)
- Umano, 1996 (Box-folder 207: 20)
- Union Nationale Inter-Universitaire, 1985 (Box-folder 207: 21)
- Strategic and Defense Studies Centre, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 207: 22)
- Former Members of Congress, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 208: 1-2)
- Forschungsinstitut der Deutschen Gesellschaft für Auswärtige Politik, 1975 (Box-folder 208: 3)
- Forum of Federations, 2004 (Box-folder 208: 4)
- Deutsche Gesellschaft für Auswärtige Politik, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 208: 5)
- Foundation for International Training, undated (Box-folder 208: 6)
- Foundation for Peace Policy, undated (Box-folder 208: 7)
- Foundation for Soviet-American Economic Cooperation, 1991 (Box-folder 208: 8)
- Freedom House, 1973-2003 (Box-folder 208: 9-10)
- Institute of International Relations, undated (Box-folder 208: 11)
- Institut Français des Relations Internationales, 1982 (Box-folder 208: 12)
- Institute of European Studies, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 208: 13)
- Institute for International Economics, 1982 (Box-folder 208: 14)
- Institute for Global Ethics, 1990 (Box-folder 208: 15)
- Institute of Public Affairs, Melbourne, 1982 (Box-folder 208: 16)
- Institute for International Studies and Training, 1982 (Box-folder 208: 17)
- Euro-Japanese Exchange Foundation, 1982 (Box-folder 209: 1)
- The Experiment in International Living, 1982 (Box-folder 209: 2)
- Federal Trust for Education and Research, 1981-1987 (Box-folder 209: 3)
- Federal Union, 1977-2001 (Box-folder 209: 4-5)
- Federation of European-American Organizations, 1983 (Box-folder 209: 6)
- Foreign Affairs Publishing, 1981 (Box-folder 209: 7)
- Foreign Affairs Research Institute, undated (Box-folder 209: 8)
- Foreign Policy Association, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 209: 9)
- Foreign Policy Research Institute, 1982-2002 (Box-folder 209: 10)
- Former Members of Congress, 1977-1989 (Box-folder 209: 11-12)
- Eisenhower fellowships, 1982 (Box-folder 210: 1)
- Encounter Magazine, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 210: 2)
- English Speaking Union, 1975-1986 (Box-folder 210: 3)
- Ethics and Public Policy Center, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 210: 4)
- Euro-Atlantic Institute, 2002 (Box-folder 210: 5)
- European-American Institute for Security Research, 1983 (Box-folder 210: 6)
- European Association for Japanese Studies, 1975-1982 (Box-folder 210: 7-8)
- European Atlantic Group, 1974 (Box-folder 210: 9)
- European Atlantic Group, London, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 210: 10)
- The European-Atlantic Movement (T.E.A.M.), 1979-1990 (Box-folder 210: 11-12)
- European Court of Human Rights, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 210: 13)
- European Cultural Foundation, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 210: 14)
- European Democrat Union, 1982 (Box-folder 210: 15)
- European League for Economic Cooperation, 1982 (Box-folder 210: 16)
- European Movement, 1982 (Box-folder 210: 17)
- History of Atlantic Movement, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 211: 1)
- Pax Democratica Distribution, 1997-2000 (Box-folder 211: 2-3)
- Arlie House, Association to Unite the Democracies, conference planning meeting, 1992 (Box-folder 211: 4-5)
- 21st Century Foundation, 1984-1994 (Box-folder 212: 1-4)
- Pax Democratica
  - General, 2000 (Box-folder 212: 5)
  - Version IV manuscript, 1997 (Box-folder 213: 1-2)
  - Version III manuscript, 1997 (Box-folder 213: 3-4)
  - Manuscript, 1996 (Box-folder 213: 5)
  - Atlantic Institute, 1964-1979 (Box-folder 214: 1-3)
  - Council on Washington State and Future, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 214: 4-5)
  - Cincinnati Council on World Affairs, 1982-1991 (Box-folder 214: 6)
  - Cumberland Lodge, 1990 (Box-folder 214: 7)
  - Dacor, 1990 (Box-folder 214: 8)
  - Journal of Defense and Diplomacy, 1987 (Box-folder 214: 9)
  - World Democracy News, 1987 (Box-folder 214: 10)
  - Delegation of the European Communities, 1978-1986 (Box-folder 214: 11)
  - Democratic International, 1985 (Box-folder 214: 12)
  - Deutsche Atlantische Gesellschaft, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 214: 13)
  - Deutschesjugend Institut, undated (Box-folder 214: 14)
  - Discovery Institute, 1993 (Box-folder 214: 15)
  - Ditchley Foundation, 1977-1987 (Box-folder 214: 16)
  - Economic Development Council of Puget Sound, 1978 (Box-folder 214: 17)
  - Education for Democracy, 1990 (Box-folder 214: 18)
  - Atlantic College, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 215: 1-2)
  - Alumni Associations, 1969 (Box-folder 215: 3)
  - Anglo-German Foundation for the Study of Industrial Society, 1973 (Box-folder 215: 4)
  - Australian National University: Strategic and Defence Studies Centre, 1984 (Box-folder 215: 5)
  - Australia/New Zealand/United States Economic Council, 1983 (Box-folder 215: 6)
  - Atlantic Info Centre for Teachers, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 215: 7)
  - Atlantic Institute, 1954-1985 (Box-folder 215: 8-10)
  - Atlantic Institute, histories, 1981 (Box-folder 215: 11)
  - Atlantic project, Nixon report, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 215: 12)
- Pax Democratica materials and correspondence, 1995-1999 (Box-folder 216: 1)
- The Atlantic Papers
  - "No. 43: Natural Gas and Economic Security,", 1981 (Box-folder 216: 2)
  - "No. 42: Nuclear Non-Proliferation and Safeguards,", 1981 (Box-folder 216: 3)
  - "No. 4: Employee Participation and Company Reform,", 1976 (Box-folder 216: 4)
  - "No. 1: Europe and the Maghreb,", 1972 (Box-folder 216: 5)
  - "No. 5: Soviet-American Relations: One-Half Decade of Détente Problems and Issues,", 1976 (Box-folder 216: 6)
  - "No. 34: Turkey, NATO and Europe: A Deteriorating Relationship?,", 1977 (Box-folder 216: 7)
  - "No. 2: Stemming World Inflation,", 1971 (Box-folder 216: 8)
  - "No. 3: The Great Power Triangle: Washington-Moscow-Peking,", 1970 (Box-folder 216: 9)
  - "No. 2: The Fate of the Pound,", 1969 (Box-folder 216: 10)
  - "No. 1: Ballistic Missile Defence and the Alliance,", 1969 (Box-folder 216:)
- Atlantic College, 1967 (Box-folder 217: 1-2)
- Atlantic Institute, 1959-1961 (Box-folder 217: 3-5)
- Atlantic College, compensation, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 217: 6-7)
- Campus unrest, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 218: 1-3)
- Student unrest, bibliography, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 218: 4)
- Academy for Contemporary Problems, 1971 (Box-folder 218: 5)
- Atlantic Council, 1961-1990 (Box-folder 218: 6-7)
- Atlantic Colleges, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 218: 8-9)
- Next Century Initiative, Seattle Group, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 219: 1)
- Next Century Initiative Principals, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 219: 2)
- The Federalist: A Political Review, Year XLII, No. 1, 2000 (Box-folder 219: 3)
- The Federalist: A Political Review, Year XLI, No. 3, 1999 (Box-folder 219: 4)
- Foreign Affairs, Vol. 77, No. 5, 1998 September-October (Box-folder 219: 5)
- Foreign Affairs, Vol. 78, No. 6, 1999 November-December (Box-folder 219: 6)
- Foreign Affairs, Vol. 63, No. 3, 1985 (Box-folder 219: 7)
- The Atlantic Papers
  - "No. 44: Economic Interests in the 1980's: Convergence or Divergence?,", 1982 (Box-folder 219: 8)
  - "No. 4: International Monetary Relations After Jamaica,", 1977 (Box-folder 219: 9)
  - "No. 2: The Road to European Union, A Plea for a Constitutional Revolution,", 1977 (Box-folder 219: 10)
- Atlantic Council of the United States (ACUS) conference, 1986-1996 (Box-folder 220: 1)
- Association to Unite the Democracies, Next Century Initiative, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 220: 2-6)
- Postwar New Order, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 221: 1-2)
- Iraq War, 1991-1995 (Box-folder 221: 3-4)
- Iraq crisis, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 221: 5-6)
- Atlantic economy, monetary matters, 1973 (Box-folder 222: 1)
- Group of Ten, 1975 (Box-folder 222: 2)
- Atlantic Community, energy politics and economics, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 222: 3)
- The International Energy Agency, 1977 (Box-folder 222: 4)
- Multinational corporations, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 222: 5-6)
- The Organization for European Economic Cooperation (OEEC), 1956 (Box-folder 222: 7)
- Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), 1958-1977 (Box-folder 222: 8-10)
- Management, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 222: 11)
- Economic growth, new economies, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 222: 12)
- Atlantic Community, economy, 1959-1976 (Box-folder 223: 1-3)
- Right-wing totalitarianism, 1971 (Box-folder 223: 4)
- Federalism, 1956-1971 (Box-folder 223: 5)
- Atlantic Community, LDCs, 1959-1974 (Box-folder 223: 6-7)
- World politics and peace, 1938-1973 (Box-folder 223: 8-9)
- Environment
  - Energy and resources, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 224: 1-2)
  - Ecology, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 224: 3)
  - Bibliography, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 224: 4)
  - Education, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 224: 5)
  - Food, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 224: 6)
- Political contributions, 1995-1998 (Box-folder 224: 7)
  Contains campaign buttons.
- Peace research, conflict resolution, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 224: 8)
- Communism, 1952-1974 (Box-folder 224: 9-10)
- Environment
  - Population, 1970-2002 (Box-folder 225: 1)
  - Transport, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 225: 2)
  - World Environment Newsletter, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 225: 3)
  - Limits to growth, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 225: 4-5)
  - Pollution, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 225: 6-7)
  - Atlantic Council of the United States (ACUS)-Battelle Pollution Conference, 1971 (Box-folder 225: 8)
  - Historic and cultural heritage, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 225: 9)
  - Housing and urban development, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 225: 10)
  - Land use and planning, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 225: 11-12)
  - Leisure, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 225: 13)
  - Council of Europe, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 226: 1-2)
  - U.K., 1972-1973 (Box-folder 226: 3-4)
  - Germany, 1973 (Box-folder 226: 5)
  - Individual countries, 1972 (Box-folder 226: 6)
  - International, 1968-1974 (Box-folder 226: 7-8)
  - Other intergovernmental organizations, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 226: 9)
  - NGOs, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 226: 10)
  - NATO, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 227: 1-3)
  - European Economic Community (EEC), 1969-1973 (Box-folder 227: 4-5)
  - Economic Commission for Europe (ECE), 1971-1973 (Box-folder 227: 6-7)
  - France, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 227: 8)
- Atlantic Community
  - The Gaps, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 228: 1-2)
  - Atlantic Union, 1940-1982 (Box-folder 228: 3-5)
- Environment
  - Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), 1970-1972 (Box-folder 228: 6-7)
  - United Nations, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 228: 8-10)
- Atlantic Community
  - Arab relations, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 229: 1)
  - Speech materials, 1965 (Box-folder 229: 2)
  - General, 1957-1979 (Box-folder 229: 3-5)
  - History, 1944-1979 (Box-folder 229: 6-7)
  - Bibliography, 1956-1974 (Box-folder 229: 8-9)
  - East/West, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 230: 1-5)
  - Political development, 1962-1973 (Box-folder 230: 6)
- NATO, 1959-1976 (Box-folder 231: 1-3)
- Atlantic Community, Atlantic Society, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 231: 4)
- NATO, 1955-1971 (Box-folder 231: 5)
- European Security Conference, Timothy Stanley, 1970 (Box-folder 231: 6)
- Atlantic Community, public opinion, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 231: 7-8)
- Russell and Gates proposals, 1999-2000 (Box-folder 232: 1)
- Committees for a Community of Democracies, history, organization, finances and board, 2000-2001 (Box-folder 232: 2-3)
- The World and the School
  - No. 4, 1965 (Box-folder 232: 4)
  - No. 6, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 232: 5)
  - No. 7, 1966 (Box-folder 232: 6)
  - No. 8, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 232: 7)
  - No. 16: Le Monde et L'Ecole, 1969 (Box-folder 232: 8)
  - No. 17, 1969 (Box-folder 232: 9)
  - No. 20, 1970 (Box-folder 232: 10)
  - No. 21, 1971 (Box-folder 232: 11)
  - No. 24: Race and International Affairs, 1972 February (Box-folder 232: 12)
  - No. 25: Europe and America, 1972 June (Box-folder 232: 13)
  - No. 26: Revolution, 1972 September (Box-folder 232: 14)
  - No. 28: Crime and Punishment, 1973 May (Box-folder 232: 15)
- "Crisis Paper No. 2: Czechoslovakia and the Balance of Forces,", 1968 October (Box-folder 232: 16)
- "The Atlantic Papers 46: China and the U.S.S.R.: Limits to Trade with the West,", 1982 May (Box-folder 232: 17)
- "The Atlantic Papers 49: East-West Strategic Trade, COCOM and the Atlantic Alliance,", 1983 June (Box-folder 232: 18)
- Foundations, European, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 233: 1-2)
- Agnelli Foundation, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 233: 3-4)
- NATO, scientific cooperation and defense, 1957-1981 (Box-folder 233: 5-9)
- Atlantic Council of the United States (ACUS), Theodore Achilles, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 234: 1-2)
- Atlantic projects
  - Multinational center, 1954-1959 (Box-folder 234: 3-4)
  - Atlantic Destiny book, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 234: 5)
  - "Atlantic Idea,", 1963-1969 (Box-folder 234: 6)
- Ford Foundation, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 234: 7)
- Atlantic Council of the United States (ACUS), certificate of incorporation, by-laws, 1961-1984 (Box-folder 234: 8)
- Alliance and democracies, 1984 (Box-folder 234: 9)
- Atlantic Council of the United States (ACUS), the problem, 1984 (Box-folder 234: 10)
- North Atlantic Foundation, 1984 (Box-folder 235: 1)
- Atlantic Council of the United States (ACUS)
  - Programs, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 235: 2-3)
  - Finances, 1984 (Box-folder 235: 4-5)
  - General, 1984 (Box-folder 235: 6-7)
  - Board of Directors, 1984 (Box-folder 235: 8)
  - Stewardship report, 1984 (Box-folder 235: 9)
  - Administration, 1984 (Box-folder 235: 10)
  - General, 1983 (Box-folder 235: 11)
- Atlantic projects
  - Leadership, 1955-1969 (Box-folder 236: 1)
  - Leadership Elite Study, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 236: 2-3)
  - Young leaders, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 236: 4)
  - Atlantic organizations, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 236: 5)
  - Civic education, 1969 (Box-folder 236: 6)
  - Cultural interchange, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 236: 7)
- Atlantic Council of the United States (ACUS)
  - Employment issues, 1984 (Box-folder 236: 8)
  - Exhibits, 1984 (Box-folder 236: 9)
- The Atlantic Community Quarterly, Vol. 6 to 10, 1968-1972 (Box 237)
- The World and the School: No. 9, 1967 March (Box 237)
- The World and the School: No. 11 to 16, 1967-1969 (Box 237)
- The Atlantic Community Quarterly, Vol. 4 to 9, 1966-1972 (Box 238)
- "International Cooperation in Science and Technology,", undated (Box 239)
- "Crisis in the Atlantic Alliance: Origins and Implications,", 1982 (Box 239)
- "NATO Today: The Alliance in Evolution,", 1982 (Box 239)
- "NATO Troop Withdrawals,", 1982 (Box 239)
- "American Troops in Europe: An Anachronism or a Necessity?,", 1972 (Box 239)
- "Wellesley Papers: A Northern Foreign Policy,", 1979 (Box 239)
- "The Eurogroup,", 1979 (Box 239)
- "Aspects of NATO: Defence Policy,", 1969 (Box 239)
- "Aspects of NATO: Political Consultation,", undated (Box 239)
- "Aspects of NATO: The Eurogroup,", 1972 (Box 239)
- "NATO: Non-Military Co-Operation in NATO,", undated (Box 239)
- "NATO: Economic Consultation in NATO,", undated (Box 239)
- "Transatlantic Partnerships and Problems: An Enquiry into Relations Between Western Europe and the United States,", 1974 (Box 239)
- British Atlantic Committee Newsletter, 1972-1973 (Box 239)
- "NATO: Past-Present-Prospectus,", 1972-1973 (Box 239)
- "CSCE: The Vienna Conference,", 1989 (Box 239)
- "Aspects of NATO: Chronology,", 1973 (Box 239)
- "Aspects of NATO: The Challenges of Modern Society,", 1979 (Box 239)
- "Aspects of NATO: Cultural Co-operation,", 1979 (Box 239)
- "Aspects of NATO: Scientific Co-operation,", 1973 (Box 239)
- "NATO: A Factual Survey of Issues and Challenges Facing the Alliance at the End of the 1990s,", 1996 (Box 239)
- "Trade Unions in Europe,", 1969 June (Box 239)
- "China, 1949-69: 20 Years of Chinese Communism,", 1969 September (Box 239)
- "Student Unrest in Eastern Europe,", 1969 October (Box 239)
- "East-West Contacts: A Monthly Review,", 1972 September-October (Box 239)
- "NATO: A Continuing Role,", 1968 (Box 239)
- "America and Europe in the 1970s: Integration or Disintegration?,", 1974 (Box 239)
- "The Atlantic Allies and the Future of Europe,", 1973 (Box 239)
- "NATO: Facts About the Activities of the Science Committee,", 1967 (Box 239)
- "NATO Orienteering: NATO Created Security,", 1973 (Box 239)
- "The Atlantic Council Security Series: NATO at 30,", 1979 (Box 239)
- "The Atlantic Alliance and the Warsaw Pact: A Comparative Study,", undated (Box 239)
- "The All-in-One Guide to European-Atlantic Organisations,", 1984 (Box 240)
- "Atlantic Convention Resolution: H.J. Res. 606,", 1975 (Box 240)
- "Political Education in the Countries of the Atlantic Alliance: Report for the Working Group on the Successor Generation,", 1980 (Box 240)
- "Transatlantic Educational Package, Youth and Pacifist Trends within the Alliance: Report of the Sub-Committee on the Successor Generation,", 1982 (Box 240)
- "What Have I Learned? Retrospect and Prospect," commencement address, Department of Political Science, 1980 (Box 240)
- "Public Affairs and the Successor Generation: A Project Report,", undated (Box 240)
- "The Present and Future of the Atlantic Alliance: How to Improve Public Understanding of Its Objectives,", 1982 (Box 240)
- "Second Anglo-American Symposium on Deterrence and European Security,", 1981 (Box 240)
- "Strengthening the Free World Through Steps Toward Atlantic Unification,", 1966 (Box 240)
- "Programme and Useful Information: Seventeenth Annual Assembly and Atlantic Congress,", 1971 (Box 240)
- The NATO Handbook, 1967 (Box 240)
- "The Atlantic Alliance: Problems and Prospects,", 1966 (Box 240)
- "The Changing Pattern of the Western World: An Information Handbook,", 1964 (Box 240)
- "The Bulletin of the National Association of Secondary School Principals: American Attitudes Toward Ties with Other Democratic Countries,", 1964 (Box 240)
- "A Report on the Strategic Importance of Western Europe,", 1964 (Box 240)
- "The Future of NATO,", 1967 (Box 240)
- "The Free Trade Area Option: Opportunity for Britain,", 1967 (Box 240)
- "World Politics and Free Trade: Britain, USA and the West,", 1968 (Box 240)
- "A New Basis for Atlantic Cooperation,", 1968 (Box 240)
- "L'Alliance Atlantique Disloquée,", undated (Box 240)
- "Notes on European and Atlantic Affairs 1945-1967," (Box 240)
- "Report of the First International Study Conference on the Atlantic Community,", 1952 (Box 240)
- "Report of the Second International Study Conference on the Atlantic Community,", 1953 (Box 240)
- "The Spirit of the Atlantic Alliance: A Progress Report,", 1956 (Box 240)
- "The NATO Parliamentarians' Conference,", 1964 (Box 240)
- "Atlantic Assembly: Proposals and Prospects,", 1965 (Box 240)
- "Défense De L'Alliance 1970-1980/Allied Defense in the Seventies,", undated (Box 241)
- NATO Handbook, 1969 April (Box 241)
- "Report on the Future Tasks of the Alliance,", 1969 (Box 241)
- "Why NATO?,", 1968 (Box 241)
- "NATO: Past, Present, Prospect,", 1969 December (Box 241)
- "Aspects of NATO: NATO, the First Twenty Years,", undated (Box 241)
- "Aspects of NATO: Chronology 1945-1969," (Box 241)
- "The General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade,", 1961 May (Box 241)
- American Council of Learned Societies Newsletter, Vol. XVI, No. 6, 1965 October (Box 241)
- ORBIS: A Quarterly Journal of World Affairs, Vol. XI, No. 1, 1967 (Box 241)
- ORBIS: A Quarterly Journal of World Affairs, Vol. X, No. 3, 1966 (Box 241)
- "European Free Trade Association: Nine Countries One Market,", 1970 (Box 241)
- "The Soviet View of NATO," speech by Leonid Brezhnev, 1967 April (Box 241)
- "Organisation for Economic Co-Operation and Development Reviews of National Science Policy,", 1968 January (Box 241)
- "The Atlantic Alliance Basic Issues: A Study Submitted by the Subcommittee on National Security and International Operations,", 1966 (Box 241)
- "The Atlantic Alliance Unfinished Business: A Study Submitted by the Subcommittee on National Security and International Operations,", 1967 (Box 241)
- "The Atlantic Alliance: Current Views,", 1967 (Box 241)
- "United States Troops in Europe: Hearings Before the Combined Subcommittee of Foreign Relations and Armed Services Committees,", 1967 (Box 241)
- "The Group of Seven Countries: New Institutions for the West,", 1994 April (Box 241)
- "Is Democratic Theory for Export?,", 1986 (Box 241)
- "Research In the International Organization Field: Some Notes on a Possible Focus,", 1952 (Box 241)
- "A Global Strategy to Meet the Global Threat: A British Initiative,", 1981 (Box 241)
- "Maritime Power,", 1980 (Box 241)
- "Europe, Japan, Canada, and The United States: The Interaction of Economic, Political, and Security Issues,", 1976 (Box 241)
- "Christian Approaches to World Security and Peace,", 1977 (Box 241)
- "U.S. Participation in International Organizations,", 1977 (Box 241)
- "Second German-American Roundtable on NATO: the Theater Nuclear Balance,", 1978 (Box 241)
- "The Atlantic Connection: An Occasional paper from the Dickey Endowment,", 1984 (Box 241)
- "Political Community at the International Level,", 1954 (Box 241)
- The Economist Diary
  - 1971-1973 (Box 242)
  - 1974-1976 (Box 243)
  - 1977-1979 (Box 244)
  - 1980 (Box-folder 245: 1)
  - 1981 (Box-folder 245: 2)
- University of South Carolina materials, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 245: 3-4)
- Gates documents, 1993-1998 (Box-folder 246: 1-2)
- The 21st Century Foundation prospectus, 1976-1990 (Box-folder 246: 3-5)
- The 21st Century Foundation materials, 1989-2004 (Box-folder 246: 6)
- Arlie House Conference on European Youth and Young Leaders, 1967 (Box-folder 247: 1)
- Projects of the Washington, D.C. Office of the Atlantic Institute, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 247: 2)
- Consortium for Atlantic-Pacific Affairs (CAPA), concept papers, 1979-1982 (Box-folder 247: 3)
- Atlantic Pacific Club, 1972-1983 (Box-folder 248: 1)
- Pacific Northwest advisors, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 248: 2)
- Atlantic Institute, 1949-1963 (Box-folder 248: 3-5)
- "The Atlantic Institute: A Prospectus,", 1960 (Box 249)
- L'Institut Atlantique, 1960 (Box 249)
- Les Cahiers Atlantiques, 1970 (Box 249)
- "Promotion and Organisation of Fundamental Research: General Report,", 1968 (Box 249)
- "Scientific and Technical Information Systems and Policies: General Report,", 1968 (Box 249)
- "Gaps in Technology Between Member Countries: General Report,", 1968 (Box 249)
- "Stopping the Spread of Nuclear Weapons,", 1967 (Box 249)
- "Toward the Reconciliation of Europe: New Approaches for the U.S., UN, and NATO,", 1969 (Box 249)
- The Atlantic Institute, 1962 (Box 249)
- "The Atlantic Papers, NATO Series I: Beyond Alliance,", undated (Box 249)
- "The Atlantic Papers, NATO Series II: Crisis Management, The New Diplomacy,", 1966 (Box 249)
- "The Atlantic Papers: The Role of Science and Technology in Atlantic Economic Relationships,", 1967 (Box 249)
- "Pour Un Message Des Peuples Libres a l'Ensemble de L'Humanite,", 1962 (Box 249)
- "The Free World's Aims for Humanity,", 1963 (Box 249)
- Atlantic Institute for International Affairs, 1972 (Box 249)
- "Next Steps in International Monetary Reform: A Hearing Before the Subcommittee on International Exchange and Payments of the Joint Economic Committee,", 1968 (Box 249)
- "The Overall Level and Structure of R&D Efforts in OECD Member Countries,", 1967 (Box 249)
- "The Atlantic Institute" pamphlet, undated (Box 249)
- Atlantic Studies/Etudes Atlantiques, 1964 (Box 249)
- "The Atlantic Institute" pamphlet, undated (Box 249)
- "The Atlantic Papers," pamphlet, 1970 (Box 249)
- "The Atlantic Institute," pamphlet, 1970 April (Box 249)
- "When the Empire Comes Homes: Consequences of the Abolition of Military Conscription in Great Britain: Discussion Paper,", 1974 February (Box 249)
- "The Atlantic Papers," pamphlet, 1969-1972 (Box 249)
- "The Atlantic Colleges: A New Concept in Education,", undated (Box 249)
- "Cultural Community and European Integration,", 1956 (Box-folder 250: 1)
- "The European Coal and Steel Community,", 1955 (Box-folder 250: 2)
- "A Case Study in British Foreign Policy Formation,", 1956 (Box-folder 250: 3)
- "The Reconciliation of France and Germany,", 1956 (Box-folder 250: 4)
- International relations
  - Public diplomacy, 1979-2004 (Box-folder 251: 1-2)
  - Foreign service, 1984-2002 (Box-folder 251: 3)
- New world order, 1991 (Box-folder 251: 4)